# Saphal Ghimire gsaphal99@gmail.com 19 March 2023

## **SUMMARY**

Accomplished software developer with 2+ years of experience in developing mobile applications. Excels in every stage of the life cycle of application development, including design creation, coding, debugging, testing, and maintenance. Advanced skills and knowledge of core programming tools with a strong background in mathematics, algorithms, and decentralized systems logic.

#### PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Programming Languages/Frameworks: Java, Dart, C, C++, Javascript, Kotlin

**Databases:** SQL, MongoDB **Tools:** Android Studio, VsCode

Others: Google APIs (Maps, Oauth), Jira, Asana, Payment Integrations (Stripe, Paypal)

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

RedChillies Labs Inc., December 2020 - Till Date

**Position:** Mobile Application Developer

- 1. Converted Figma designs into application code using Java as the framework
- 2. Integrated different API endpoints to communicate with the backend services
- 3. Integrated Paypal gateway APIs to manage the payment services on the platform.
- 4. Implemented a CI/CD pipeline using Fastlane and Firebase to automate app building and distribution to testers.
- 5. Integrated third-party services such as Push Notification and Google Location Services
- 6. Used version control tools such as GitHub and Bitbucket to track and maintain changes to the project
- 7. Write UI and unit tests to identify app malfunctions
- 8. Worked on in-house projects "Fanscan" and "Funkyland"

Pastel Software Solutions., November 2019 - November 2020

**Position:** Mobile Application Developer

## Responsibilities:

- 1. Internship for three months as part of the curriculum for the course.
- 2. Converted Figma designs into application code using Java as the framework
- 3. Write UI tests to identify app malfunctions
- 4. Projects Involved Vuze

#### IT CERTIFICATIONS

- Android App Development by IIT Nepal from March 1, 2019, to May 31, 2019
- Advanced PHP Course by IIT Nepal from July 1, 2018, to October 1, 2018.
- Video Mapping of Cultural Heritage Sites by Alleys Map on August 6-7, 2018.

# **EDUCATION**

- Bachelors of Science in Computer Science and Information Technology, Kathford International College of Engineering and Management, Tribhuvan University 10/2016-10/2020. The percentage is 79.62%.
- Science Stream, Moonlight Higher Secondary School, Higher Secondary Education Board (HSEB) 07/2014-07/2016. The Percentage is 66.30%.
- SLC, Annal Jyoti Secondary Boarding School, Nepal Government 04/2003 04/2014. The Percentage is 86.68%.

# PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

- 7 Days Web Designing Bootcamp organized at Kathford International College.
- Getting started with Blockchain organized on ICT Startup and Innovation Mela.
- Learn MERN Stack Bootcamp organized at Himalaya College of Engineering
- Mask RCNN Practical Learn Deep Segmentation on Udemy.
- Introduction to Python Programming on Udemy.

#### **SCORES**

IELTS - Overall 7.0 (R 7.5 L 7.0 W 7.0 S 6.5) - Test Taken on July 28, 2022.

## **HONORS**

- Nominated as Youth for the year 2018/2019 (Youth program consists of the brightest and most innovative students, leaders, developers, and technology enthusiasts from colleges and universities of Nepal).
- 2nd position in Himalayan Exhibition (Hex Code Jatra) of 'HEx-2019" on July 28-30, 2019.
- Exhibitor in ICT Startup and Innovation Mela on 20-21 December 2019.
- Mentor in Design 1.0 at Kathford International College on July 29, 2019.
- Participation in National CIST Quiz Contest organized by Tribhuvan University on September 4, 2018.
- Microsoft Word Specialist for Word 2013 on February 4, 2018.